Guide to the Albert Léon Guérard Papers, 1909-1959 M0016
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England] (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 18. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Jun 29, 1916.
  - 19. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Jul 21, 1916.
  - 20. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Jul 25, 1916.
  - 21. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Aug 2, 1916.
  - 22. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Nov 1, 1916.
  - 23. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Nov 8, 1916.
  - 24. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Dec 5, 1916.
  - 25. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Dec 16, 1916.
  - 26. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Dec 18, 1916.
  - 27. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Oct 21, 1919.
  - 28. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Mar 17, 1920.
  - 29. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], May 5, 1920.
  - 30. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Nov 16, 1920.
  - 31. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Sep 12, 1920.
  - 32. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Jul 7, 1923.
  - 33. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Sep 10, 1923.
  - 34. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Sep 12, 1923.
  - 35. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Dec 27, 1923.
  - 36. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Mar 18, 1924.
  - 37. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Nov 5, 1924.
  - 38. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Nov 7, 1924.
  - 39. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Dec 8, 1924.
- CORRESPONDENCE OUT (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1. Algernon Cecil, Oct 21, 1933.
  - 2. Rev John Haynes Holmes, May 14, 1940.
  - 3. M. Albert Camus, Jan 19, 1946.
  - 4. James T. Farrell, May 26, 1946.
  - 5. James T. Farrell, Jun 7, 1946.
  - 6. Horace (?) Mann, May 17, 1954.
  - 7. Bishop Parsons, Oct 8, 1954.
  - 8. Waldo Frank, Feb 21, 1957.
  - 9-11 Edward Parsons, Mar 22, Dec 19, 1957, June 28, 1959.
- Guérard - PUBLIC ISSUES, [1916 to 1956] (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - a) Introduction by Guérard to following copies.
    - 1. Monsieur Cohn, Jan 27, 1916.
    - 2. Dr. Axson, enroute to Europe, Jan 24, 1917.
    - 3. to Mrs. Guérard by Dr. Axson, Apr 5, 1919.
    - 4. Albert (?), Sep 34, 1939.
    - 5. Mr. Farrar, Jan 10, 1941.
    - 6. Mrs. Irita Van Doren, Jun 9, 1941.
    - 7. Dr. Ray Lyman Wilbur, Jun 12, 1941.
    - 8. US Foreign Policy Statement, Aug 21, 1941.
    - 9. to Simon & Schuster, Apr 30, 1942.
    - 10. Wire to President Roosevelt, N.D.; (copy)
    - 11. Donald McKay, Oct 16, 1942.
    - 12. Dr. Maxim Newmark, Jan 3, 1942.
    - 13. National Inventors Council, Mar 30, 1942.
    - 14. to Guérard from Andrew Hershell of LIFE Magazine, Sep 14, 1942.
    - 15. Dumas Malone, Oct 16, 1942.
    - 16. “Safety Valve”, Editor S.F. Chronicle, Jan 31, 1944.
    - 17. Messr. Chester Rowell & Clark Eichelberger, Mar 4, 1944.
    - 18. Unknown Correspondent, Oct 4, 1944.
    - 19. W. A. Willibrand, Oct 6, 1944.
    - 20. Mr. Bliven, Oct 26, 1944.
    - 21. Prof. Henri Peyre, Nov 3, 1944.
    - 22. Miss Kirchway, May 19, 1945.
    - 23. Editor, ORT Economic Review, May 18, 1945.
    - 24. Prof Donald S. Traill, May 22, 1945.
    - 25. Commander H. Stassen, Jun 2, 1945.
    - 26. Unknown (editor), Jun 2, 1945.
    - 27. Prof. Waldemar Gurion, Jan 6, 1946.
    - 28. Trent E. Stanford, Nov 28, 1947.
    - 29. Thirina?, May 21, 1951.
    - 30. to Guérard from Jean Lafitte [Conseil Mondial de la Paix, Palais Lia Prague], Nov 3, 1953.
    - 31. Jean Lafitte, Nov 24, 1952.
    - 32. Mr. Fischer (author), Apr 6, 1953.
    - 33. Editor, N.Y. Times, Apr 16, 1954.
    - 34. Editor, S.F. Chronicle, Apr 16, 1954.
    - 35. Editor, N.Y. Times, Aug 31, 1954.
    - 36. Prof Northrop, Sep 28, 1954.
    - 37. Count Richard Coudenhove-Kalergi, Oct 15, 1954.
    - 38. Editor, S.F. Chronicle, Nov 29, 1954.
    - 39. Editor, N.Y. Times Mag., Jan 27, 1955.
    - 40. Jefferson School of Science, Mar 23, 1955.
    - 41. to Guérard from Kay Boyle, Mar 4, 1955.
    - 42. Kay Boyle - reply from Guérard stapled to above, Mar 4, 1955.
    - 43. Editor, N.Y. Times, Nov 3, 1955.
    - 44. Prof Harry Levin, Jan 4, 1956.
    - 45. Editor, Architectural Forum, Jan 17, 1956.
    - 46. Lewis Mumford, Jan 17, 1956.
    - 47. Dean Robert E. Fitch, Jan 19, 1956.
    - 48. Monsieur Herbert Luethy, Jan 26, 1956.
    - 49. Andrew Hershell
    - 50. La Carmagnole de 1944, N.D.
    - 51. Substitute for Rubber in Tread of Auto Tires, N.D.
    - 52. Editor, Antioch Review, N.D.
    - 53. Editor, New Republic, N.D.
- Guérard - PUBLIC ISSUES, [1956 -] (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1. Herbert Luethy, Jan 27, 1956.
  - 2. to Guérard from Felix Morrow, May 3, 1956.
  - 3. reply to Felix Morrow, May 5, 1956.
  - 4. reply to Felix Morrow, May 6, 1956.
  - 5. Mrs. Hartley, Jun 7, 1956.
  - 6. Editor, N.Y. Times, Jun 7, 1956.
  - 7. Editor, N.Y. Herald-Tribune, Jun 19, 1956.
  - 8. Editor, The Nation, Jun 23, 1956.
  - 9. Editor, S.F. Chronicle, Jul 4, 1956.
  - 10. Editor, Palo Alto Times, Jul 24, 1956.
  - 11. Editor, The New Yorker, Sep 19, 1956.
  - 12. Mr. Brier, Sep 19, 1956.
  - 13. Editor, The Nation, Oct 7, 1956.
  - 14. Stuart Hughes, Sept 1, 1956.
  - 15. “Petite Cousine Aimee”, Nov 17, 1956.
  - 16. to Guérard from Society for Prevention of WW III, Nov 19, 1956.
  - 17. “Wallace”, Nov 21, 1956.
  - 18. Monsieur Frederick Sieburg, Dec 2, 1956.
  - 19. Albert Simard, Dec 6, 1956.
  - 20. David Packard, Dec 12, 1956.
  - 21. Walter Millis, Dec 17, 1956.
  - 22. Editor, the Nation, Dec 25, 1956.
  - 23. Editor, the Nation, Dec 25, 1956.
  - 24. Elmer Davis, Dec 27, 1956.
  - 25. Editor, S.F. Chronicle, Dec 25, 1956.
  - 26. David C. Williams, Mar 9, 1957.
  - 27. Editor, Aryan Path, Mar 9, 1957.
  - 28. to Guérard from Simon & Schuster, Apr 24, 1957.
  - 29. reply to Richard Grossman, May 3, 1957.
  - 30. Edward Darling, May 8, 1957.
  - 31. Monsieur le directeur, Le Monde, Paris, May 29, 1957.
  - 32. “Mr. Opitz”, Oct 26, 1957.
  - 33. M. Lincoln Schuster of Simon & Schuster, Nov 13, 1957.
  - 34. Editor, N.Y. Times, Dec 7, 1957.
  - 35. Editor, New Yorker, Dec 18, 1957.
  - 36. George Brazziller, Jan 18, 1958.
  - 37. Sir Harold Nicolson, Feb 8, 1958.
  - 38. Henri Peyre, Feb 26, 1958.
  - 39. Editor, Palo Alto Times, Mar 25, 1958.
  - 40. Edward L. Bernays, Mar 29, 1958.
  - 41. Edgar Ansel Mowrer, Jun 14, 1958.
  - 42. Prof. Garrett Mattingly, Jun 25, 1958.
  - 43. George Brazziller, Jun 28, 1958.
  - 44. Editor, Christianity Today, Jun 30, 1958.
  - 45. Editor, the Nation, Sep 3, 1958.
  - 46. Editor, Palo Alto Times, Sep 15, 1958.
  - 47. Royce Brier, Sep 18, 1958.
  - 48. United Federalists, USA, Sep 27, 1958.
  - 49. Mark Van Doren, Sep 28, 1958.
  - 50. Dr. Arthur Upton Pope, Mar 23, 1959.
  - 51. Editor, ADA, Mar 25, 1959.
  - 52. I.F. Stone, Apr 23, 1959.
  - 53. Pres of USA, May 23, 1959.
  - 54. Editor, The Nation, Jun 1, 1959.
  - 55. Editor, Palo Alto Times, May 26, 1959.
  - 56. David C. Williams Editor, ADA World, Jun 9, 1959.
  - 57. Rev. John Robertson Macartney, Jul 10, 1959.
  - 58. “Robertson”, Aug 8, 1959.
  - 59. “Robertson”, Aug 11, 1959.
  - 60. Editor, N.Y. Times, Aug 13, 1959.
  - 61. Miss Cogswell, Sep 23, 1959.
  - 62. Prof. Mattingly, Oct 9, 1959.
  - 63. Editor, S.F. Chronicle, N.D.
  - 64. Morris Rubin, N.D.
- Guérard MANUSCRIPTS (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1. Ramblings of a Cheerful Ghost
  - 2. Stalin - An Appraisal of the Man and his Influences
  - 3. David Starr Jordan - As a Writer
  - 4. Conrad the Novelist. Ms fragment, [UNK] pg. design, 1st p. of ch. 1 typed w/hand corrections, [UNK]
- Guérard - INTERNATIONAL LANGUAGES (Box 2, Folder 15-17)
  - 1. Esperanto, 19 printed items.
  - 2. Notebooks, 2. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 3. Lecture Notebook, 1. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 4. International Auxiliary Language Assn [IALA] Reports, etc., 1926-1940 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 5. Notes on International Language (Interlinguistic Problems), poem by Zamenhof. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 6. IALA handbooks, IDO pamphlet. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 67 pamphlets and printed matter pertaining to international languages. (Box 3, Folder 23-27)
  - Albert Guérard - Epaves., [Poems in manuscript] (Box Book)